# Ali Al-Mawla

E-mail: ali.mawla1999@hotmail.com

Address: Lebanon, Beirut

Phone: +961 71215108

### **Profile**

An experienced and dedicated data analyst with several years of experience identifying efficient and problem areas within data streams while communicating needs for projects. And an full stack web developer seeking to elevate my skills and knowledge to the next level.

## Core Skills

- Team Player
- Experienced in Leadership
- Decision Making
- Interpersonal Communication Skills
- Hard Working
- · Creative Problem Solving

## Work experience

Lebanese Army

10/2017 — Present

Data Analyst

- · Adjutant at the Lebanese Army.
- Perform exploratory data analysis and discover notable relationships.
- Analyze data sets and help companies make decisions based on findings.

#### CIS Innovation Hub

summer 2023

Full Stack web developer internship

- Played an integral role in crafting interactive websites that captivated users with dynamic elements and real-time interactions, with one noteworthy project being the CIS Innovation Hub website.
- Acquired proficient, hands-on expertise in seamlessly integrating JSON APIs during my full-stack web developer internship. Skillfully integrated JSON APIs into diverse web applications, facilitating smooth data interchange between front-end and back-end functionalities.

#### **CIS Innovation Hub**

summer 2023

Computer Instructor for Special Needs Children

- As a computer teacher for children with special needs at a summer camp, I designed an inclusive and adaptive curriculum that catered to the diverse abilities and learning styles of each child.
- Recognizing the importance of individual attention, and providing personalized guidance and encouragement to each student throughout the camp.

Ali Al-Mawla

#### Lancaster Plaza

Captain Waiter

04/2015 — 11/2017

- Ensure diners are receiving high-quality service.
- Assisting guests with making menu choices in an informative and helpful fashion.

Mawla Cell 02/2010 — 01/2019

Sales Representative and Customer Service

Buying and selling phones and accessories at my dad's shop.

## Education

Computer Science 10/2019 — 2024

**MUC University** 

Under graduated student with GPA 3.6.

Mathematics 10/2016 — 11/2017

Lebanese University

Accomplished first year in 2017.

## Skills

-C++ - Java

-JavaScript - Python
-Flutter - HTML
-CSS - Oracle
-SQL Server - PHP

-Laravel - Data Structure

-Cyber Security - Networking & server config

-Microsoft Office Suite

## Languages

- English
- Arabic (Native Language).

## Certificates

- · Leadership certificate from the Italian Army
- Theoretical and Applied Analysis certificate from the German Army
- International Cyber Crime Fundamentals Training Certificate "CYBER SAFETY ASIA PROGRAM" from the Australian Army

## References

References available upon request.

Ali Al-Mawla 2